umbel.com 2017-11-13

# Privacy Policy | Umbel

Effective Date: 06/14/2017

**“Client”** means a customer of Umbel.

**“Client Data”** means information hosted by Umbel on behalf of its Clients.

**“Collected Information”** means information Umbel collects from Visitors and/or End Users, including Website Navigational Information.

**“End User”** means an individual that uses the Service.

**“Individual”** means an individual whose information is collected by Umbel or transferred to us by our Clients.

**“Legal Processes”** means judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, court orders or other legal processes.

**“Service(s)”** means Umbel’s software as a service platform available at https://app.umbel.com.

**“Services Agreement”** means a written agreement for Service between Umbel and a Client.

**“Umbel”** or **“Company”** means Umbel Corp.

**“Umbel’s Digital Properties”** means, collectively, https://app.umbel.com and www.umbel.com.

**“Visitor”** means an individual that visits the Website.

**“Web Site Navigational Information”** means certain information collected by Umbel using tracking technologies, such as cookies and web beacons.

Umbel is committed to protecting the privacy of Visitors, End Users and Individuals. This Privacy Policy describes Umbel’s privacy practices in relation to the use of Umbel’s Digital Properties. Umbel collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information.

Umbel’s Digital Properties may contain links to other web sites. Umbel takes reasonable measures to ensure that Umbel’s Digital Properties are free of malware, but Umbel is not responsible for the information practices, content, or terms of service of such other web sites. Umbel encourages you to review the privacy policies of other web sites to understand their information practices and terms of service.

Umbel participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Umbel is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s www.privacyshield.gov/list.

Umbel participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Umbel is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s www.privacyshield.gov/list.

Umbel is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Umbel complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions. With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Umbel is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Umbel may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the www.privacyshield.gov/welcome, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

### Types of Information Collected

To receive Service information, Visitors may have to provide Umbel with personal contact information, such as name, email address and company name. To use the Service, End Users may have to provide Umbel with their contact information, such as name, business email address and company name.

Umbel may also obtain some information about Individuals from third party sources for analysis and to better understand the Individuals’ social presence. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our Service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly.

As you navigate Umbel’s Digital Properties, Umbel may also collect Web Site Navigational Information, including standard information from your web browser (such as browser type, browser version, and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on Umbel’s Digital Properties (such as the web pages viewed and the links clicked). For more information, please see Section 5 Web Site Navigational Information below.

### Use of Information Collected

Umbel uses Collected Information to deliver Services, and for other internal product development efforts. For example, if you fill out a “Contact Us” Web form, Umbel will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Service. Umbel may also use Collected Information for marketing purposes. For example, Umbel may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in Umbel, the Service, and to send you information regarding Umbel and its partners, such as information about promotions or events.

Umbel uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve Umbel’s Digital Properties. Umbel may also use Web Site Navigational Information in combination with other Collected Information to provide Visitors and End Users with personalized information about Umbel.

Umbel uses information about Individuals only to provide Services to Clients.

Umbel may link or combine Collected Information with information we get from other sources to help understand your needs and provide you with better Service. Umbel will use Collected Information and Web Site Navigational Information only for the purposes described above and, except as noted in this Privacy Policy, will not disclose or distribute such information to third parties other than its agents, partners and service providers.

### Web Site Navigational Information

Umbel collects Web Site Navigational Information as you navigate Umbel’s Digital Properties. This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information Umbel may collect, typical methods used for collection of such information, and how Umbel may use this information.

Umbel and its third party partners, such as marketing partners and analytics providers, use tracking technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts. We also use technologies for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking Visitors and End Users’ movements around these properties and to gather demographic information about our Visitors and End Users as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of such tracking technologies by our partners and providers on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to make your interactions with Umbel’s Digital Properties easy and meaningful such as to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. We may use information cookies in combination with Collected Information to provide you with information about Umbel and the Service. Visitors and End Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use Umbel’s Digital Properties, but your ability to use some features or areas of the Umbel’s Digital Properties may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. Umbel uses this information for various purposes such as tracking and monitoring End Users’ and Visitors’ activities on Umbel’s Digital Properties. For example, Umbel uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which End Users and Visitors navigate Umbel’s Digital Properties. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve Services, to improve marketing, analytics, and site functionality.

#### Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting

We partner with third party ad networks to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if located in the European Union click here). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash and HTML 5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash and HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML 5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs, please click here.

UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, NEGLIGENCE, SHALL UMBEL BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, LOSS OF DATA OR PROFIT, ARISING OUT OF THE USE, OR THE INABILITY TO USE, THE WEBSITE OR MATERIALS ON THIS WEBSITE, EVEN IF UMBEL OR AN UMBEL AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. SOME STATES DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.

### Sharing of Information Collected

Umbel may share Collected Information with Umbel’s agents so that these agents can contact Visitors and End Users who have provided contact information on our behalf. Umbel may also share Collected Information with Umbel’s agents to ensure the quality of information provided.  
Umbel may also share Collected Information with Umbel’s third party partners who may use such information to communicate with you about products and services that we think will be of interest to you.

Umbel uses a third-party intermediary to manage credit card processing. This intermediary is not permitted to store, retain, or use billing information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on Umbel’s behalf.

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Umbel reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information of End Users or Visitors if Umbel reasonably believes that disclosure is necessary to protect Umbel’s rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, and to investigate fraud; if necessary to perform credit checks or collect or report debts owed to us; and/or to comply with Legal Processes.

Umbel reserves the right to transfer any personally identifiable information we have about you in the event of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personally identifiable information you have provided through our Umbel’s Digital Properties in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. Umbel may also share personally identifiable information of End Users or Visitors with persons who perform certain services for us, such as our accountants, auditors, attorneys and the like, but only to the extent necessary for them to perform their services to us. We expect such service providers to comply with our privacy and information security standards.

### Communication Preferences

Umbel offers End Users and Visitors who provide contact information a means to choose how Umbel uses the information provided. You may manage receipt of email communications from Umbel by clicking on the “to manage your subscriptions or to unsubscribe, click here” link located on the bottom of the Umbel’s emails. Additionally, you may send a request specifying your communications preferences to contact@umbel.com. If you no longer wish to allow us to share your information with third parties, you may opt-out from such sharing by contacting that third party directly.

### Correcting and Updating Your Information

Umbel is committed to ensuring that the personally identifiable information that it collects regarding its End Users and Visitors is reliable for its intended uses and is accurate, complete, and current. If Umbel discovers that corrections are necessary with respect to any such information, it will promptly update its records. Upon request, Umbel will provide you with information about whether we hold, any of your personal information. End Users may also update or change their registration information by contacting Umbel at contact@umbel.com. Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be handled within 90 days. We will respond to your access request within 30 days. We will retain your information for as long as your Client account is active or as needed to provide you Services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us as described below. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Umbel will not review, share, distribute, or reference any Client Data except as provided in the Services Agreement (or similar agreement), or as may be required by Legal Processes, and will host Client Data solely to facilitate the processing and use of the Client Data by its Clients. Individual records of Client Data may be viewed or accessed by Umbel only for the purpose of resolving a problem, support issues, or suspected violation of the Services Agreement, or as may be required by Legal Processes. End Users are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of their Umbel usernames and passwords. If Client Data includes personally identifiable information subject to the protections of the European Union’s Data Protection Directive, Client will remain responsible for such information vis-à-vis the Individual in accordance with the relevant EU provisions, although, as set forth in the Services Agreement, Umbel will cooperate with the Client as may be necessary to ensure that individuals’ rights to access and correct such information are respected. Umbel permanently deletes or destroys Client Data residing on its servers promptly upon the termination of a Client relationship.

#### Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

Umbel collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

#### Access and Retention of Data Controlled by our Clients

Umbel acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Umbel has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his or her query to Umbel’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Umbel to remove the data, we will respond to its request within 30 days.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients only for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Umbel will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our Service Agreements.

To the extent that Umbel provides Client Data or Collected Information to its agents, partners or service providers, Umbel takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure that its agents, partners or service providers either abide by Umbel’s privacy practices as reflected in this Privacy Policy or by substantially equivalent policies.

Although we strive to make security a priority, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on Umbel’s Digital Properties, you can contact security@umbel.com.

Umbel’s Digital Properties may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Umbel reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy, only with the prior approval of TRUSTe. Umbel will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Policy through Umbel’s Digital Properties at least thirty (30) calendar days prior to the change taking effect.

### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California’s Shine the Light law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83, California residents have the right under certain circumstances to request, once per year, information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes, including a list of the categories of information we have shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. To make such a request, please contact us by emailing contact@umbel.com or by mailing Umbel Marketing, 800 West Cesar Chavez St. Suite B101, Austin, TX 78701.
